- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh... *
-*哦...*
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
* *
**
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
* *
**
- Ooh, this grass feels great
between my toes.
- 哦，这草感觉棒极了
我的脚趾之间。
Hey, Patrick, are you enjoying
our early morning nature hike?
嘿，帕特里克，你享受吗？
我们清晨的自然徒步旅行？
- [yawning]
- [打哈欠]
[burbling]
[咕噜声]
[birds chittering]
[鸟儿叽叽喳喳]
It's cutting into
my early morning nature nap.
它切入
我清晨的自然小睡。
[thuds]
- Come on, Patrick.
[重击声]
- 来吧，帕特里克。
If you want to stay healthy,
you have to embrace nature!
如果你想保持健康，
你必须拥抱自然！
- Okay!
- 好的！
[silly skipping noises]
[愚蠢的跳跃声]
* *
**
[shimmering sting]
both: Ooh!
[闪烁的刺痛]
两人：哦！
- Cool ice cave!
- 酷冰洞！
- Ohhhhhhh...
- 哦哦哦...
This whole place
is a frozen treat!
这整个地方
是冷冻食品！
[licking noises]
[舔舐声]
- No, Patrick! Don't lick
the ice, you're gonna get stuck!
- 不，帕特里克！不要舔
冰，你会被困住的！
- Uh.
- 呃。
Now he tells me.
现在他告诉我了。
[crying and straining]
[哭泣和紧张]
- Okay, Patrick.
Everything is going to be fine.
- 好吧，帕特里克。
一切都会好起来的。
Just don't panic.
只是不要惊慌。
[panicked screaming]
[惊慌尖叫]
* *
**
- I panicked, SpongeBob.
- 我惊慌失措，海绵宝宝。
- Don't worry!
Hot chocolate solves everything.
- 不用担心！
热巧克力解决一切。
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
* *
**
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
Hot! Hot! Hot!
热的！热的！热的！
Hot! Agh!
热的！啊啊！
[sighs]
[叹气]
[thuds]
[重击声]
* *
**
- Uh...
- 呃...
- Okay, Patrick.
- 好吧，帕特里克。
That's enough nature
for you today.
自然就够了
今天给你。
* *
**
[sniffing]
Oh?
[嗅嗅]
哦？
Ah.
啊。
[purring]
Squeaky, squeaky!
[咕噜声]
吱吱，吱吱！
* *
**
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
* *
**
[purrs]
Mehh.
[呼噜声]
嗯。
[gentle harmonica music]
[轻柔的口琴音乐]
* *
**
- See ya later, Patrick.
- 稍后见，帕特里克。
* *
**
Gary, I'm home!
加里，我回来了！
Boy, this backpack got heavy.
天啊，这个背包变重了。
* *
**
- Meow!
- 喵！
* *
**
Meow.
- [sniffing]
喵。
- [嗅嗅]
* *
**
Ah!
啊!
* *
**
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
* *
**
- Boy, those natures hikes
really put hair on my tongue.
- 男孩，那些大自然的远足
真的让我舌头发毛。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[alarm rings]
[警报响起]
[machines whirring]
[机器呼呼地响]
* *
**
- [growling]
[alarm rings]
- [咆哮]
[警报响起]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Agh-agh-agh!
啊啊啊啊！
[panting]
Squeaky! Squeaky!
[气喘吁吁]
吱吱！吱吱！
[happy grunting]
[快乐的咕噜声]
[groans]
No squeaky.
[呻吟]
没有吱吱声。
* *
**
- I'm on my way to work, Gary.
See ya tonight!
- 我正在上班的路上，加里。
今晚见！
- [imitating grunts]
- [模仿咕噜声]
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
- Meow?
- 喵？
* *
**
- [happy chuckling]
- [高兴地笑]
Squeaky! Squeaky!
吱吱！吱吱！
[happy grunting]
[快乐的咕噜声]
[happy ukulele music]
[快乐的尤克里里音乐]
* *
**
- [humming]
Ah!
- [嗡嗡声]
啊！
* *
**
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
* *
**
- [happy grunting]
- [快乐的咕噜声]
- Good morning, Squidward!
- 早上好，章鱼哥！
- It was.
- 是的。
Agh!
啊啊！
[thuds]
[重击声]
* *
**
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
- I do relish...
- 我很喜欢...
* *
**
making the relish!
令人津津有味！
* *
**
[rapid whirring]
[快速呼呼声]
- [panicked grunting]
- [惊慌的咕哝声]
[whirring]
- SpongeBob!
[呼呼]
- 海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
- Yes, Mr. Krabs?
- 是的，蟹老板？
You call me?
你打电话给我吗？
- Can you step into
the dining room
- 你能进入吗
餐厅
for one moment, son?
儿子，一会儿？
[boinging]
Huah! Wha-wha-wha-wha-huah!
[轰鸣声]
哇！哇-哇-哇-哇-哇！
Front and center,
and ready for duty, sir!
前面和中间，
准备好执勤了，先生！
[gasping]
[喘气]
- That's the man
who smashed my mailbox, officer!
- 就是那个男人
谁砸坏了我的邮箱，警官！
- Well?
- No, Mr. Krabs,
- 出色地？
- 不，蟹老板先生，
I'd never do
something like that!
我永远不会这样做
类似的东西！
- Of course you wouldn't!
- 你当然不会！
It's just this loser's word
against yours, boy-o.
这只是这个失败者的话
反对你的，男孩。
They can't convict you for that.
他们不能因此定罪你。
- Phew.
- 唷。
- He ruined my fountain!
- 他毁了我的喷泉！
- Yeah, yeah!
That's the guy!
- 是啊是啊！
就是那个家伙！
- Mr. SquarePants,
I'm afraid you're under arrest.
- 方裤先生，
恐怕你被捕了。
[handcuffs jangle]
[手铐叮当声]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
- But--but Mr. Krabs.
- 但是 - 但是蟹老板先生。
I didn't do anything.
我什么也没做。
I was framed!
我被陷害了！
It wasn't me!
不是我！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Don't worry, boy-o!
- 别担心，小伙子！
I'm right behind you!
我就在你身后！
Look alive, Mr. Squidward!
看起来还活着，章鱼哥先生！
I'm gonna visit SpongeBob
in the big house.
我要去拜访海绵宝宝
在大房子里。
You are manning the grill!
你正在负责烧烤！
- [yelling]
Ow!
- [大喊]
噢！
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
- Ah?
- 啊？
[growls]
Agh!
[咆哮]
啊啊！
[clanging]
- [yells]
[叮叮当当]
- [大喊]
* *
**
They let you out already?
他们已经放你出去了吗？
Ugh, you look terrible,
SpongeBob!
呃，你看起来很糟糕，
海绵宝宝！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Well, get the food ready.
It's almost time for lunch!
- 好吧，把食物准备好。
快到吃午饭的时间了！
[clangs]
[叮当声]
- Food?
- 食物？
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
* *
**
[war cry]
[战争呐喊]
Agh!
啊啊！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
* *
**
[war cry]
[战争呐喊]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
* *
**
[gurgling]
[淙淙]
[triumphant yell]
[胜利的呐喊]
[boings]
[嘘声]
[clangs]
[叮当声]
[pounding noises]
[撞击声]
* *
**
Huh?
啊？
- Well, it's about time!
- 好吧，是时候了！
* *
**
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
* *
**
- [steaming and gagging]
- [热气腾腾、作呕]
- [panicked yelling]
- [惊慌失措的叫喊]
- [munching]
Ah! Ah!
- [咀嚼]
啊！啊!
[gagging]
[作呕]
- [slurping]
Agh!
- [发出声音]
啊啊！
[overlapping shouting]
- This is ridiculous!
[重叠的喊叫]
- 这太荒谬了！
- Is this a restaurant
or a garage?
- 这是一家餐馆吗
或者车库？
- [panicked shouting]
- [惊慌失措的喊叫]
Agh! Agh!
啊啊！啊啊！
- [crunching]
Huh?
- [嘎吱嘎吱]
啊？
- SpongeBob, what did you do?
- 海绵宝宝，你做了什么？
The patties taste horrible!
Everybody hates them!
肉饼味道太难吃了！
大家都讨厌他们！
- Unh.
- 嗯。
[growling]
- What the--
[咆哮]
- 什么是--
[panicked yelling]
[惊慌失措的叫喊]
SpongeBob's gone crazy!
海绵宝宝疯了！
Run for your lives!
为你的生命而奔跑！
- [grunts]
Spongy! Spongy!
- [咕哝]
海绵状！海绵状！
[all screaming]
[growling]
[所有人尖叫]
[咆哮]
[overlapping shouts]
[重叠的喊声]
[panicked yelling]
[惊慌失措的叫喊]
- This is Perch Perkins
live at the Krusty Krab,
- 这是鲈鱼珀金斯
住在蟹堡王，
where we understand that a local
fry cook has just gone nuts.
我们了解到当地
炒菜厨师刚刚疯了。
- [grunting]
- Ooh!
- [咕哝]
- 哦！
This just in...
Ow!
这只是在...
噢！
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
* *
**
Why did you have to go nuts
on company time, boy-o?
为什么你必须发疯
在公司时间，男孩？
I'm gonna lose so much money.
我会损失很多钱。
- I didn't go nuts, Mr. Krabs.
- 我没有发疯，蟹老板。
They must've mistaken me
for someone else.
他们一定误会我了
为了别人。
I'm innocent!
我是无辜的！
[squeaking]
[吱吱声]
- Oh? Squeaky, squeaky?
- 哦？吱吱、吱吱？
[growling]
[咆哮]
- Save it for the judge, boy-o.
- 把它留给法官吧，小伙子。
Come clean! Nobody else
even looks like you!
来干净吧！没有其他人
连长得都像你！
[eerie swell]
[诡异的膨胀]
Except that guy.
除了那个家伙。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
* *
**
- [gasps]
- [growling]
- [喘气]
- [咆哮]
Squeaky, squeaky!
吱吱，吱吱！
- Local scientists now believe
that the rampaging fry cook
- 当地科学家现在相信
那个狂暴的鱼苗做饭
is actually
a prehistoric "cave sponge,"
实际上是
史前的“洞穴海绵”
once thought to be extinct.
- Ah! Get him off!
一度被认为已经灭绝。
- 啊！把他放开！
- See! I didn't
destroy any property!
- 看！我没有
摧毁任何财产！
It was that Cave Sponge!
就是那个洞穴海绵！
* *
**
- [sniffing]
- Aw. He's just lost and scared.
- [嗅嗅]
- 噢。他只是迷失和害怕。
He just needs
another sponge to talk to.
他只需要
另一块可以交谈的海绵。
- Shortly thereafter,
- 此后不久，
Mr. Krabs and SpongeBob
went to City Hall
蟹老板和海绵宝宝
去了市政厅
to confront the wild beast.
去对抗野兽。
- We did?
- 我们做到了？
* *
**
- [panicked grunting]
- [惊慌的咕哝声]
* *
**
- Don't worry, officer.
I'm a fellow sponge.
- 别担心，警官。
我是一块海绵。
He'll listen to me.
他会听我的。
* *
**
- Unh?
- 呃？
[sniffing]
- Ooh?
[嗅嗅]
- 哦？
[giggles]
[sniffing]
[咯咯笑]
[嗅嗅]
SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
* *
**
- Unh.
- 嗯。
Spongy Spongy.
海绵状的 海绵状的。
- Oof!
- 噢！
Now we're getting somewhere!
现在我们已经取得进展了！
Sooo...can you please
go downstairs now
苏...可以请你吗
现在下楼去
and turn yourself in
to the police?
并自首
报警？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Hello!
- [growls]
- 你好！
- [咆哮]
- Okay, Spongy Spongy.
- 好吧，海绵海绵。
I respect that.
I'll leave you alone.
我尊重这一点。
我会让你独自一人。
- [growls]
Uh.
- [咆哮]
呃。
[happy grunting]
Oh!
[快乐的咕噜声]
哦！
Squeaky, squeaky!
吱吱，吱吱！
* *
**
- Oh, you like that, huh?
- 哦，你喜欢这样，是吗？
[squeaking]
Ah!
[吱吱声]
啊！
- [imitating grunts]
- [模仿咕噜声]
[both squeaking]
[两者都吱吱作响]
[upbeat crescendo]
[欢快的渐强]
* *
**
[all cheering and applauding]
- [whistling]
[大家欢呼和鼓掌]
- [吹口哨]
* *
**
[thuds]
[重击声]
- [happy grunting]
- [快乐的咕噜声]
* *
**
[frustrated shouting]
[沮丧的喊叫]
* *
**
- Spongy Spongy, wait!
- 海绵宝宝，等等！
Wahh!
哇！
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
* *
**
Well, I talked him down.
好吧，我说服了他。
Hooray.
万岁。
Oh, please don't put
Spongy Spongy in jail!
哦，请不要放
海绵宝宝进监狱啦！
- Nobody's gonna
put him in jail son.
- 没人会
儿子，把他关进监狱。
He just saved the town millions
by demolishing city hall.
他刚刚为小镇拯救了数百万美元
通过拆除市政厅。
It was due
to come down next week.
本来是由于
下周下来。
- Ah! Spongy Spongy is free!
- 啊！海绵宝宝是免费的！
- [grunts]
Spongy Spongy.
- [咕哝]
海绵状的 海绵状的。
Spongy Spongy!
海绵海绵！
- And so, the savage beast
finally soothed,
- 所以，野蛮的野兽
终于平静下来
life in Bikini Bottom
returns to normal...
比基尼泳裤的生活
恢复正常...
if only for this episode.
如果只是为了这一集。
This is Perch Perkins--
这是珀奇·帕金斯——
Ow!
- [grunts]
噢！
- [咕哝]
- [groaning]
For Bikini Bottom News.
- [呻吟]
比基尼泳裤新闻。
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
* *
**